《十三号仓库》前情提要
Previously on warehouse 13
几年前  我发誓你说过
Years ago, I swear you said
你不过是个普通教授
You were just a simple professor.
漏说了这个装满神奇藏物的最高机密仓库
You left out the top-secret warehouse full of madcap.
克劳迪娅  你就是入侵者
Claudia. You're the breach.
芝麻开门
Knock knock.
你的哥哥约书亚来找你
Your brother Joshua visits you
跟你说他没死
And tells you he's not dead?
帮我把他救回来
Help me bring him back.
谢谢你没放弃
Thanks for not giving up.
克劳迪娅知道了太多关于仓库的事
Claudia learned a great deal about the warehouse,
她会成为隐患
Which could become problematic.
你知道该怎么办
You know what the options are.
曼哈顿岛  四百年前
Manhattan Island, Four Hundred Years Ago
上帝降临之时
When He comes
让这些元素成为他的力量
Let these elements be his strength
和我们的希望
and our hope.
纽约城  现代
New York City, Present Day
还有这个
And this.
什么藏物能干出这种事
What artifact did that?
还是说那就是藏物
Or is that the artifact?
出自一位鲜为人知的雕刻家
It was created by a little-known sculptor
沃尔特・伯利
Walter Burleigh,
昨晚被盗
And it was stolen late last night
地点是纽约一家高档拍卖行
From a high-end auction house in New York.
不过问题并不在此
But that's not the issue.
问题在于它是怎么被盗的  因为...
The issue is how this thing was stolen, because...
我只不过想弄明白
I'm trying to figure out why
为什么我才刚回到这个世界
After I just got back into this world
你就迫不及待地要把我扫地出门
You're in such a rush to shove me out the door.
因为我花半辈子把你救出来
Because I didn't spend half my life trying to save your life
不是让你回来上网看视频的
So you could surf the net and watch youtube.
抱歉  我不过想补习过去十二年的时事
Well, excuse me for trying to catch up on current events
和全球形势罢了
And the state of the world in the last 12 years.
拜托  我们在工作
Hey, we're working.
就在这里
We're working right here.
阿迪  抱歉
Artie, I'm sorry,
但我得找份工作
But apparently I have to find a job.
而且我不知道该怎么
Don't know exactly what I'm gonna put
在简历里把这段空白补上
In that little gap in my resume.
那就把你怎么走的经过写上去啊
Well, hey, what about what got you there in the first place?
-你  -干嘛
- You!  - What?
你没事可做吗
Don't you have something to do?
比如去联邦监狱待着
Like stay out of federal prison?
你不是应该给我写份
And aren't you supposed to be writing me
完整技术图
A full technical schematic
说明你是如何入侵仓库的吗
On how you racked my warehouse?
伙计  就在楼上  快写完了
Yeah, buddy. It's upstairs. It's almost finished.
那好  我要你马上写完它
Well then, I want you to finish it,
每个重定向和反斜线符都标清楚
And I want every redirect and every backslash.
去  马上
Go. Now.
写完之后  你就去仓库
And then after that, you're going into the warehouse
把你进来时弄断的线
And you're gonna re-wire what you unwired
重新接上
When you broke in.
我想把你也弄断
I'd like to unwire you.
小脚轻快的脚步声
The patter of little feet.
那么  阿迪
All right, so, Artie,
一个恶心的雕像被盗
Somebody boosts an ugly sculpture.
跟我们有什么关系
Why does that involve us?
关键在于
Okay, what is significant here
这东西是怎么被盗的
Is how this thing was stolen.
这起盗窃案根本不可能发生
I mean, this theft was...impossible.
有高端报警系统
There was a high-end alarm system,
八英寸厚的墙壁
Eight-inch thick walls,
密封的储藏室
Sealed vault.
上一秒雕像还在
So one second that sculpture was there,
下一秒就没了
Next second gone.
但也只是一起精心策划的艺术品盗窃案
But it's still just a well-executed art theft.
它可没有大叫着"仓库"
I mean, it doesn't automatically shout "warehouse,"
对吗
Does it?
没有东西会叫喊着"仓库"
Things rarely shout "warehouse."
它们都是小声嘀咕
They usually whisper,
"这可奇怪了"
"Hey, that's a little odd."
它们就是那样
That's what they do.
我也可能出错  也许没问题
Well, I could be wrong. I mean, it could be nothing.
但我很可能是对的
But I'm probably not wrong.
上次我弄错是1987年6月
Last time I was wrong was 1987, June.
等等  说那事
Stop right there. That.
我想听那件事
I want to hear more about that.
没门  出发
Not a chance. Go.
好的
Okay.
我们走
Here we go.
走喽
Going.
走  快走
Go, go, go, go.
阿迪
Hey, Artie.
你知道我爱纽约
Hey, uh, you know I love New York.
-很棒的城市  -那是
- Oh, a great town.  - It is.
所以我想
So I was just thinking
也许你能弄点
Maybe you guys could kick down some
演出门票或是...
Tickets to a show, or...?
那得看是什么演出了
Well, it depends on the show.
-真的  -假的  快滚
- Really?  - No. Get out of here.
演出
Show.
好像你还有时间
Like you're even gonna have time
看那傻兮兮的音乐剧
For a stupid musical.
还得让我掏钱
Or that I'd even pay for it.
非百老汇的剧又不是很贵
Off Broadway's not that expensive.
纽约
New York
克鲁瑟拍卖行
Carruther's auction house
向来以保安水准为荣
Pride itself on security.
这桩盗窃案真是难倒我们了
This theft has us stumped.
监控录像什么也没拍到
Video surveillance shows nothing.
我想你们用的电子门锁
I'm assuming you use an electronic lock
会记录一切活动
That records all activity.
记录显示门根本没开过
And it says the door never opened.
谁是卖家
Who's selling the piece?
一位地产商
Private estate.
他决定要拍卖
He decided to auction
在他接触过两个买家之后
After he was approached by two interested parties,
都是大买家
Both with deep pockets.
拍卖时间是什么时候
When is this auction, uh, scheduled?
本来是今天
It was for today.
不好意思  你们能不能转个身
Uh, I hate to ask, but would you mind?
也许其中一位买家
You know, maybe one of these interested parties
厌恶竞争
Hates competition.
这么说这位买家
Which would mean that said party
借用藏物的神力
Has an artifact that lets them pull off
来做个了结
An impossible heit.
要么简单的答案是
Or the simple answer,
有内贼
An inside job.
她确实值得好好调查
She does bear scrutiny.
跟我来
Follow me.
好的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
她跟你不是一类人
She's out of your league.
你知道我这类人是怎样的吗
How do you know what my league is?
我可没问阿迪要
Not that I ask for them,
可我就是有季赛门票
But I've got season tickets.
太棒了  我喜欢
That's good. I like it.
盗贼偷走的那件工艺品
So the thief take one piece.
是这里最值钱的吗
Was it the most valuable one in here?
那倒不是
Oh, far from it.
但青菜萝卜各有所爱
But there's no accounting for taste.
说不好
Oh, I don't know.
有些东西就是经典
Some things are just classic.
皮特
Pete.
能过来一下吗
Come here for a second?
不如我待在储藏室
Why don't I, uh, stay here in the vault
来处理这些"仓库的事"
And look for anything, you know, "warehousey",
你去查查那两个买家好吗
And you go check out those two interested parties?
我们一起行动
Well, wouldn't things go quicker
效率不是会高一些吗
If we just worked together?
要是你在泡妞儿的话  就不会快
Well, not if you're on a date.
这样的话我们能双管齐下
Look, this way we can cover twice as much ground,
你甚至能赶得及
And maybe you'll even get done in time
请短裙美女去看演出
To take, uh, skirt girl to a how.
两个有兴趣的买家  是吗
Two interested parties, huh?
我去拿他们的资料
I'll get their info.
好极了  我和你一起去
Great. I'll, uh, go with.
各就各位
Batter up.
拉蒂默探员
Agent Lattimer?
吉尔伯特・列本
Gilbert Radburn.
在很多建筑物上见过您的大名
Yeah, I've seen your name on a few buildings.
这就是我把名字刻在上面的原因
Good. That's why I put it up there.
需要我帮什么忙
What an I do for you?
您感兴趣的那件雕塑昨晚被盗了
You were interested in the sculpture that was stolen last night,
伯利的那件
The Burleigh?
是的
I was.
你可能会想
And as you might guess,
我讨厌失败
I'm not fond of losing.
特勤局到底想知道什么
What's the Secret Service's interest?
它是如何被盗的
How it was stolen.
也就是说
Which was?
能告诉我您昨晚在哪吗
You mind telling me where you were last night?
我可没必要去偷
Ha. I have no need to steal.
有时候倒不是为了偷
Well, sometimes it's not about stealing.
是为了征服感
You know, it's about conquering.
好比把您的名字刻在建筑物上
Like putting your name on a building.
我昨晚和朋友一起
I was with friends.
一整晚
All night?
这是个不夜城
This is the city that never sleeps.
需要名字吗
You want names?
那再好不过了
Yes, please. That would be swell.
您为什么对伯利的作品感兴趣
Also, why the Burleigh?
有什么特别之处吗
What's so special about it?
情人眼里出西施  拉蒂默探员
Eye of the beholder, agent Lattimer.
情人眼里出西施
Eye of the beholder.
好  我会把名字给你
Yeah, I'll get you those name.
谢谢您  先生
Thank you, sir.
探地雷达
Ground Penetrating Radar
怎么了
What's up?
赶紧过来
You should get back here.
查到什么了
You got something?
在一个木箱后面有发现
I found something behind one of the crates,
但你亲自过目会更说得清
But it's easier to show and tell.
是什么
What is it?
你肯定不会相信的  但是...
You're not gonna believe this, but...
我闻到"软糖"了
I smell fudge.
马上到
I'll be right there.
你说的那是什么
What are we talking about here?
就在这儿  你来看
Well, it's right here. You can see it.
看吧
Right?
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
好的
Okay.
慢慢来
Easy.
皮特  别
Pete, no.
不行
No.
藏物的神力
Artifact behavior
通常需要接触人体才能施展  对吗
Usually require a human element, right?
当心
Just be careful.
好的
Okay.
-好吗  -知道了
- Okay?  - Okay.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
快看啊
Check it out.
不可思议
It's crazy.
这就是我最想拥有的藏物之一
Okay, you see this is one of those artifacts that I'd really like to keep.
皮特  放进来
Pete, put it in.
下面是见证奇迹的时刻
Hey, Rocky, watch me pull a rabbit out of my hat.
酷毙了
Now that's cool.
我就知道会这样
That's what I thought.
怎样  你掐我我会疼吗
What? That pinching cause pain?
不是  那个我知道
No. No, I know that.
这根羽毛
But the feather,
只能在肘以下部分起作用
It only works up to your elbow.
所以还不足以进来拿走雕像
So not enough to get in and out with the sculpture.
正是  所以这只是藏物的一部分
Exactly, which means that this is only part of the artifact.
还不是完整的
It's not the whole thing.
至少缩小范围了
Oh. At least that narrow it down.
目标是一只能穿墙走壁的
We're looking for an arts-dealing bird
买卖工艺品的鸟
That walks through wall.
正如阿迪所说
Like Artie always says...
别排除任何可能性
Never rule anything out.
给我看看
Show me.
好的
Okay.
像是印第安人的东西
Looks native American.
对  它应该是某件东西的一部分
Yeah, we think it fell off something larger,
仪式物品
A ceremonial object,
拐杖  和睦烟斗
A walking stick, a peace pipe maybe.
还有鸟
Or a bird.
对这东西的主人有线索了吗
Yeah. Any guesses to who this thing belonged to?
也许是那两个
Uh, well, maybe one of the two guys
雕塑买家的其中之一
Who wanted to buy the sculpture,
但还有一个我们还没问过话
But we haven't interviewed one of them yet.
拉本很富有  没必要冒险
Radburn's too rich to risk it.
他出手比唐纳德・特朗普还阔绰
He could outbid Donald Trump.
可以排除他的嫌疑
I think we an rule him out.
别排除任何可能性
N-never rule anything out.
那好
Okay, uh, well,
另一个买家也是有钱的主
The second guy's a rich dude.
叫做杰弗里・韦佛
His named is Jeffrey Weaver
杰弗里・韦佛
Jeffrey Weaver
是亚历山大・韦佛的儿子吗
Is that the son of Alexander Weaver?
阿迪  亚历山大・韦佛是什么人
Um, Artie, who is Alexander Weaver?
曾经
Yeah, was.
他勒索钱财
He was an extortionist,
是个房地产骗子
A real estate swindler.
还是个文物破坏者
And a ravager of cultures.
绝非善类
Not a nice man.
已经死了
Now deceased.
对了
And...yes.
儿子杰弗里住在纽约
Son Jeffrey lives in New York.
所以...
So...
除非这小子和他父亲不是一丘之貉
Look, unless the acorn fell very far from the tree,
否则就得悠着点了
Watch your backs.
到底是哪个
Which one are you?
看看  是不是这个
Let's see. Is it that one?
别紧张  放松点
Chill, parky.
还好吗
Uh, how's it going?
你害怕我会把这房子给烧了吗
You mean are you scared I'm gonna burn the house down?
紧急出口标识得很清楚
Emergency exits are clearly marked.
你觉得我对你是假惺惺的吗
You think my concern for you is insincere?
我觉得你该把电缆剪递给我
I think you should pass me the cable shears.
那些就是
Those.
对继续生活感到不安吗
So...anxious to get on with your life?
令人震惊的洞察力
Such shocking insight.
我的气味告诉你的吗
Did my aura tell you that?
你把约书亚逼太紧了
You're certainly pushing Joshua.
他就要别人推一把
Only 'cause he needs it.
你对他有意思
Oh, you do have a thing for him.
你在扯开话题
You're changing the subject.
是你提起他的
You brought him up.
既然你把他救出来
Now that you've saved him,
你一生的工作也告终了
Your life's work is complete,
这让你很害怕
And that cares you.
所以你把自己的追求转嫁到他身上
So you're forcing your own need for a purpose onto him.
天才  不用催眠就说中了
Genius. And all done without a couch.
我得付你多少  弗洛伊德医生
How much do I owe you, Dr. Freud?
如果约书亚能有所成就
If Joshua accomplished great things,
那么你的牺牲也值了
Then your sacrifice is justified.
但你同样害怕孤单
But you're also afraid of being alone.
孤身一人
Truly alone.
反正我不喜欢你  随你怎么说
It's okay if I don't like you, right?
那是
Of course.
可你喜欢我
But you do.
杰弗里・韦佛寓所
Jeffrey Weaver's Penthouse
韦佛先生马上就过来
Mr. Weaver will be right with you.
谢谢
Thank you.
打电话给警察  案子破了
Call the cops. Crime solved.
这跟你们想的不一样
It's not what it looks like.
不是吗  因为看来
No? Because what it looks like
像是你私藏赃物
That you're in possession of stolen goods.
仔细看一看
Take a closer looks.
这不是被偷的那一件
That's not the one that was stolen.
这个系列的雕塑有四件
There were four in the series,
每件都是以四种元素之一来命名
Each named for one of the four elements.
这一件是火
This one is fire.
被偷的那件是风
The stolen one is wind.
可以跟拍卖行确认一下
Check with the auction house.
你怎么区分它们的
How can you tell 'em apart?
要么你是行家里手
You're a trained expert
有一双洞察细节的火眼金睛
With a scrupulous eye for detail.
要么你看一眼底座上的铜牌
Or you read the brass plaque on the base.
火
Fire
杰弗里・韦佛
Jeff Weaver.
麦卡・百玲
Myka Bering.
幸会
Pleasure.
好吧
Uh, right.
能告诉我们您昨晚在哪吗
Um, you mind telling us where you were last night?
主持新奥尔良儿童医院的一个慈善活动
Hosting a charity event For the children's hospital in New Orleans.
有钱  长得帅  喜欢小孩
Rich, good looking, likes kids.
现在是谁约会来啦
Who's on a date now?
好吧  你刚才说一共有四件雕塑
Okay, uh, you said that there were four sculpture...
土  风和火对吗
Earth, wind, and fire?
真爱这些家伙
Love those guys.
应该是岩  风  火  和水
Rock, wind, and fire, actually, and water.
没错
Right.
这是艺术家对印第安人
It's the artist's tribute to native American
造物神话的赞美
Creation myth.
印第安人
Native Americans, huh?
-你对那很在行吗  -不过是业余爱好
- You into that stuff?  - Well, it's an interest.
你不会碰巧丢了一根羽毛吧
You wouldn't happen to be missing a feather would you?
也许是从一件
Maybe off something
能让你穿墙走壁的东西上掉下来的
that lets you walk through walls?
你刚说什么
What'd you just say?
你脸色可不好啊  杰弗里
You got a lousy poker face there, Jeffy.
新奥尔良在哪  坐飞机三小时就能到吗
New Orleans is what? A three hour flight away?
你仍属于嫌疑犯
You're still on our suspect list.
拉赛尔  进来
Lacell, get in here.
站在那别动
Whoa. Hey. Hold it right there.
不要动  把手举起来
Don't move. Let me see your hands.
怎么了
What is it?
这位仁兄也在列本工地
This dude was at Redburn's Construction site.
是他  他当时瞪了我一眼
Yeah, he was giving me the stink-eye.
不要紧  他的名字叫拉赛尔
It's all right. His name is Lacell
他为我工作
He works for me.
我们来决定要不要紧
We'll decide when it's all right, okay?
他也为列本工作
He also works for Radburn.
一言难尽
It's...it's complicated.
好  等等  你同时为韦佛和列本工作吗
Okay, wait. You work for Weaver and Radburn?
听着  拉赛尔没问题的
Look, Lacell's not the problem.
如果你所说的有人穿墙而入是真的
If what you said about someone walking through walls I true,
这件雕塑就不安全了
The sculpture isn't safe.
你认为他们下一步会来偷它  对吗
You think they're coming after this one next, don't you?
我们就在这里
We're standing right here.
我们能保护它
I think we got it covered.
谢了  但我自己就能保护好它
Thank you, but I can provide my own protection.
我们不是建议你
That's not an offer, okay?
如果有人穿墙而入
If somebody's walking through walls,
美国政府需要知道这个人是谁
The United States government
他是怎么做到的
needs to know who and how.
我能告诉你的就是
All I can tell you I that
这件雕塑就是下一个目标
This sculpture is the next target,
所以请让我将它转移到一个安全的地方
So please let me move it to a secure location.
好的  请等一下
Okay, well, hold on.
看这是啥  小警徽
What's that, badgey? Hmm?
好的  抱歉
Oh, okay. Sorry.
小警徽说我们得跟雕塑在一起
Badgey says we stay with the sculpture.
它去哪  我们就去哪
So wherever it goes, we go.
别动  千万别动
No, no, no, no.
别动那盘还没下完的棋
Don't touch that in the middle of the game.
-你跟谁下  -我自己
- With whom?  - Myself.
白棋已经被黑棋逼到一个死角
White's been backed into a corner by black.
我在等灵光乍现的时刻
I'm waiting for a eureka moment
救白棋一命
To save white's butt.
等多久啦
Been waiting a while? Huh?
三个月了
Three months.
干嘛问这个
Why?
克劳迪娅仔细看过这盘棋了
Oh, Claudia was looking it over.
发现你处境艰难
Noticed you were in a bit of a pickle.
她发现我处境艰难
She noticed I was in a pickle.
那个小妖女在哪
Where is the little demon?
她在里面
Oh, she's in there.
她还有活要干  她…
She's got work to do. She...
阿迪  阿迪
artie...artie.
她只是在休息
She's taking a break.
她很累了
She's been working very hard.
我讨厌你这副表情
I hate that look.
-克劳迪娅  -又来了
- Claudia...  - Here it comes.
需要一个家
Needs a home.
这不是人道协会  她不是无家可归的小猫
This is not the humane society. She's not a stray cat.
她不会留在这的
She's not staying here.
弗雷德里克夫人有些坐立不安了
Mrs. Frederic is getting antsy as it is.
我不是说让她留在这
I'm not suggesting she stay here.
阿迪  你可以给她牵线搭桥
Artie, you can pull strings...
麻省理工  加州理工
M.I.T., CalTech.
-拜托了  -她需要挑战
- Please.  - She needs a challenge.
-是啊  -阿迪  她需要有人做伴
- Yeah.  - Artie, he needs people.
她已经有约书亚了
She's got Joshua.
约书亚有自己的路要走
And Joshua's on his own path.
没错  他俩都很聪明
Yes, they're both brilliant,
但他是个科学家  而她是个实干家
But he's a researcher, and she's a doer.
她需要跟同类人在一起
She needs people like her.
跟她一样傲慢无礼  不合群  头脑发热
Brash, rude, anti-social, impulsive?
我们在说克劳迪娅  不是你
We're discussing Claudia, not you.
你在对我人身攻击
See, that's kind of a low blow.
你傲慢  无礼…
You're brash, rude...
你在干什么  不行  不行
What are you doing? No, no, no, no!
行  行  就是行
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
将军
Check.
我真该下地狱
I'll be damned.
也许吧  但这话不该由我来说
Well, maybe, but I'm not one to judge.
白棋赢了黑棋九步
White beats black in nine moves.
雕塑还好吗
Hey, is the sculpture okay back there?
它很好
Yes, it's fine.
我也很好  顺带说说
I'm...I'm fine too, by the way.
谢谢你的问候
Thank you for asking.
你能让那开车的家伙悠着点儿吗
Hey, would you tell chief leadfoot to take it easy?
还要多久才能到机场
And how much longer till we reach the airport, anyway?
皮特  一切正常吗
Pete, I everything okay?
皮特
Pete.
停车  快停车
Stop the truck. Stop the truck!
皮特  你还好吗
Pete, are you okay?
皮特  看着我
Pete, look at me.
快停下
Hey, stop!
皮特
Pete?
快叫一辆救护车
I need an ambulance right away.
皮特
Pete.
老搭档
Hey, partner.
感觉怎样
How are you feeling?
疼
Sore.
浑身都疼
Everywhere.
想吃曲奇
Need cookie.
你昏迷了好一阵子
You've been out for a while.
能想起什么来吗
Remember anything?
我身体里的分子重组
I had my molecule rearranged,
然后被推出了一辆正在行驶的卡车
And got shoved out the side of a moving truck.
差不多也就这些了
That about sums it up.
毫无疑问  你刚才一定想得头疼
Not surprisingly, it give you quite a headache.
我告诉了阿迪
You know, I told Artie what you said
你昏迷前跟我说的那件鹿皮大衣
About the buckskin coat before you passed out.
还有印第安造物神话
And the creation myth.
他在查着呢
He's doing his thing.
是啊  我不明白
Yeah, I don't get it.
他足可以去抢诺克斯堡[美国国家金库]
I mean, this guy could be robbing Fort Knox.
为什么要偷雕塑
Why the sculpture?
这就是我们要解的谜团  不是吗
Guess that's our little puzzle, isn't it?
是那个帅哥
Mm. The pretty boy.
他来这干什么
What is he doing here?
杰弗里让你做了免费全身检查
Jeff got you a free, multi-point inspection.
确保你身体的每个部位都正常
Make sure all your part are where they belong.
原来是杰弗里
Oh, Jeff did.
没错  是他
Yes, Jeff did.
这家医院归他所有
He, um, owns the hospital,
是他盖的还是怎样
Or built it or something.
那可真是手到擒来
Well, that's handy.
他邀请我吃晚餐
He asked me to dinner.
-现在都凌晨三点了  -医院的餐厅
-It's 3:00 a.m.  - well, in the cafeteria.
-有钱人啊  -但我拒绝了
- Big spender.  - But I said no.
你应该去的
Ah, you should go.
不  我应该跟你在一起
No, I should stay here with you.
-不  -皮特
- Nah. No.  - I mean, Pete...
-麦卡  -皮特
- Myka.  - Pete.
这家伙了解底细
This guy knows what's going on.
你该去的
Go for it.
用上你的美人计
You know, use your feminine wiles.
微笑
Smile.
你笑起来的样子很好看
You're pretty when you smile.
真的吗
I am?
真的
Yeah.
你的意思是我不笑会怎样
So what does that mean when I'm not smiling?
挺吓人的
Kind of frightening.
头部伤口疼  护士快来
Head injury. Nurse.
不会是因为我说过的话才走吧
Something I said?
我正想去告诉你
I was just gonna come tell you.
我就在这呢
Here I am.
没错  你说得对
Yeah, you were right.
我必须走
I have to go.
一百八十度大转弯啊
Zero to 180.
我不是让你今天就走
I didn't mean today.
我只不过在用激将法
I was just looking for some forward momentum.
我知道  阿迪打了几个电话
Yeah, well, Artie made a few calls.
欧洲核子研究中心有一个职位空缺
And, uh, there's a position at CERN.
我该去的
I should take it.
是千载难逢的机会
It's once in a lifetime.
你要去瑞士吗
You're going to Switzerland?
-没错  -跟原子打交道
- Yeah.  - Smashing atoms?
正如你说的
Like you said,
我不能把余生都浪费在
Can't spend the rest of my life
上网和听斯普林斯汀的歌上面
Listening to Springsteen and surfing the web.
如果两个空间之间的壕沟
If an inter-dimensional rift
都不能阻止你我相见
Can't keep me from being in touch with you,
区区几千英里可以吗
You think a few thousand miles will?
你给我小心点
Well, you better.
我已经说得很清楚了
Because I think I've demonstrated
我会穷追到底的
I will hunt you down.
知道
Yeah.
过来抱抱
Well, come here.
高兴点
Come on.
皮特没事了  但其他人可能会受伤
Pete's fine, but somebody else could get hurt.
那件鹿皮大衣是从哪里来的
I mean, where does that buckskin coat come from?
它跟雕塑到底有什么联系呢
Is it connected to the sculpture somehow?
有成千上万
There are hundreds
关于这些印第安人造物的传说
Of these Native American creation myths.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
我还是认为那根羽毛
I still think that the feather, however,
是最好的线索
Gives us our best clue.
羽毛主要是被
Anyway, the feather was predominantly used
一些特拉华的部落所用
By the Delaware nations,
还有被...
And also by the...
对了  雷纳佩部落
Aha. By the Lenape tribe.
是他们把曼哈顿卖给了荷兰人
They're the one who sold Manhattan to the Dutch
换回价值二十四美元的艺术品和手工制品
For 24 bucks worth of arts and craft.
可真不是笔好买卖
That's not a great deal.
话可不能这么说
You had to be there.
根据雷纳佩部落的传说
And according to Lenape legend,
世界是由四种元素的灵魂所创造
The world was created through the spirits of four elements.
四种  火  赐予我们灵魂
Four. Fire, which gave us our soul.
风  赐予我们呼吸
Wind, our breath.
水  带来死亡
Water, death.
太奇妙了
It's fascinating.
还有岩  它赐予世界...
And rock, which have the w...
琳娜
Leena.
岩赐予世界具体形态
Rock gave the world...solidity.
所以拥有鹿皮大衣的人就可以控制形态
So someone has a buckskin coat that manipulate solidity.
不会吧
No.
我觉得这整件事有一种规律
I think that this whole thing could be a pattern.
如果存在可以控制其他元素的物品
Because if there are artifact that control the other elements,
一旦有人获得了这些物品
And somebody were to acquire those artifacts,
这个人就可能拥有
That somebody would have
无穷大的力量来...
Immense power over...
控制世界
The world.
这危险可不小
At the risk of sounding dramatic.
你可从没被这些东西吓到
That's never stopped you before.
那是当然
That's true.
妈妈
Mama?
皮特  干嘛这么久才接
Pete, what took you so long?
听着
Uh, listen.
杰弗里・韦佛
Jeffery Weaver...
这个人需要重新调查
I think that that guy needs a second look.
麦卡正在调查他
Myka's taking a look at him now
还一边吃着干火鸡  蔬菜糊
Over dried turkey, mushy vegetables,
还有木薯布丁
And tapioca pudding.
好的  你还在医院吗
Okay. You're still in the hospital?
我从一辆铁皮货车里被丢了出来
I got pushed out of the side of a steel truck.
我在疗伤
I'm recuperating.
好的  等会儿再疗
Yeah, well, recuperate later.
趁麦卡支开了韦佛
While Myka's keeping Weaver busy,
我要你去搜查他的公寓
Uh, I'm gonna need you to toss his apartment.
他为什么要偷自己的东西
Why steal his stuff from himself?
故布疑阵吗
Weave our guy?
告诉我你发现了些什么
Well, tell me what you find out,
我就告诉你
And I will let you know.
这真浪漫
It's very romantic.
我让弗娜把蒸汽保温餐桌打开
I had, uh, Verna turn up the steam tables.
图得就是个气氛
It's all about atmosphere.
你很懂得如何讨女孩子欢心
Well, you sure know how to wow a girl.
这可是我的绝招
It's my best move.
你怎会进了特勤局呢
So what made you join the Secret Service?
要么进那里要么进监狱
It was either that or prison.
开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
那你呢
What about you.
你到底是做什么的
I mean, what is it you do exactly?
拿债券利息
Accrue interest.
再投资
Re-invest.
想用钱做些善事
Try to do something good with it.
活得很滋润嘛
That's a nice life.
这得看你是怎么得到这一切的
Yeah, well, it depends on how you got it.
你的父亲
Your father.
我的父亲  没错
My father, yeah.
而你不想
And you don't...
你不想重蹈他的覆辙
You don't want to follow in his footsteps.
是这样吗
Is that it?
我想推翻他走过的路
I want to erase his footsteps.
怎么了
What?
我只是在想
I'm just trying to decide
我面前坐着的是个好人还是坏人
If I'm sitting here with a good guy or a bad guy.
你知道几年前谁是列本的生意伙伴
You know who was in business with Radburn years ago?
另外一个想要雕塑的人
The other guy who wanted the sculpture?
是的  杰弗里・韦佛的父亲
That's right. Jeffery Weaver's father.
他们俩那时拼命
And both those guys tried to push really hard at that time
想卖掉这四座雕像
To sell them, all four of the sculptures.
我知道了
Yeah.
他们干了什么
What do they do?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我猜
I guess, you know,
当把四座雕像摆在一起时  就会有事发生
Something happens when you put all four sculptures together.
很可能是
My best guess, something...
坏事
Bad.
是的  坏事
Bad. Something bad.
在他住所有所发现吗
You find anything at Weaver's yet?
还没有
No, I don't know.
这房子很平常
This place is clean.
如果他有那件大衣  他很可能...
If he's the guy with the coat, he probably...
-老天  -怎么了
- Oh, come on.  - What?
可能没什么  我过会打给你
It's probably nothing. I'll call you back.
不  等等  怎么了
No, no, no. wait, wait. What?
开玩笑  太简单了
You got to be kidding me. What a hack.
找到了
Bingo mania.
你们到底在找什么东西
So what are you really after in all this?
别找政府做借口唬我
And don't tell me the government needs to know.
我是为那件大衣而来的
I'm here for the coat.
是的  政府想要它
And, yeah, the government actually does want it.
有些东西
There are certain things
不该让它在世间流传
That just shouldn't be out in the world.
我同意
True.
但你只对雕塑感兴趣
But, you, you're only interested in the sculptures.
为什么
Why?
它们并不那么值钱
They're not that valuable.
我认为一起创造出来的事物
I think things that were created together
就该在一起
Belong together.
不管是谁干的
Whoever's doing this,
你还没排除嫌疑
And I haven't ruled you out yet,
我也在收集它们
I was also collecting them.
如果四个雕塑聚齐  会发生什么
What happens when the four sculptures are together?
说实话  杰弗里  你该告诉我
Seriously, Jeff, you should tell me,
在某人...
Before somebody...
失陪一下
Just give me a seond.
皮特  你没事吧
Pete? Is everything okay up there?
没事  我在韦佛的家里
Yeah, I'm at Weaver's.
什么  你为什么...
What? Wh? What are you
他有间密室  算是伯利的祭坛
The guy's got a secret room that's a shrine to Burleigh.
他一定把伯利碰过的东西都买下了
He must have bought up everything the guy ever touched.
有一点可以肯定
Whatever's going on,
你男朋友脱不了干系
Your boyfriend's neck deep in it.
我会处理的
I'll wrap this up then.
我们该上楼了吧
So we should probably head upstairs, huh?
我倒宁可去你家坐坐
You know, I'd really rather go back to your place.
好笑的是
You know, it's funny.
通常美女对我说这话  我都会心花怒放
I usually like it when a beautiful woman says that.
确实挺好笑
That is funny. That is funny.
我最恨的就是我的男友欺骗我
Because I never like it when my date lies to me.
跟你说
You know,
伯利娶了个雷纳佩族姑娘
Burleigh was married to a Lenape woman.
而那些雕像
And the sculptures
就像把钥匙
Are some kind of a key
通往一个神圣地洞
To a sacred, underground cave.
通往一个神圣的什么
To a sacred what?
地洞
A cave.
据说洞里有四样
Uh, it says it ontains four offerings
献给造物主的贡品
To the spirit of creation.
他把这个地洞的地点
Somehow he hid the diretions to the cave
藏在了雕像中
In the culptures.
所以那四座雕像
So those four sculpture,
是张地图
See, they're a map.
如果集齐四个雕像
If you put the four sculptures together,
就能知道地洞在哪里
They tell you where this cave is.
是的  但该怎么做  阿迪
Yeah, but how, Artie?
我们漏了什么
I mean, we're missing something.
列本先生  我们发现这人想闯进来
Mr. Radburn, we found this man trying to break in.
你是拉赛尔吧
It's Lacell, right?
你在我这里的工作是什么  拉赛尔先生
What do you do for me, Mr. Lacell?
地质勘测  先生
Geological surveys, sir.
是的  你负责察看地下有什么
That's right. You see what's underground, don't you?
而你现在却溜到了半空中
And yet here you are, lurking very high above ground.
有何有趣的发现
Find anything interesting?
没有 先生
No, sir.
你不太会说谎  拉赛尔先生
You're not a very good liar, Mr. Lacell.
你为韦佛先生工作
And you work for Mr. Weaver.
别试图抵赖
Don't waste your breath with denial.
他戴着吗
Was he wearing it?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
让我看看
Let me have it.
它是什么意思
Tell me about this.
无关紧要
It's nothing.
我父亲给我的
My father gave it to me.
你是说你舅舅吧
Don't you mean your uncle?
我说过了  你不擅长说谎
As I said before, deception is not your strong suit.
沃尔特・伯利是你舅舅  对吧
Walter Burleigh was your uncle, wasn't he?
不然你以为我为什么会请你
Why do you think that I hired you?
我曾希望你带我找到那个地方
I had hoped you would lead me to the place.
你舅舅把地洞的线索藏进了他的作品
Your uncle hid clue to the sacred cave in his art.
这是什么
What's this?
水  岩  风
Water, rock, wind.
很有用
Well, that's helpful.
我知道怎么排列雕塑位置了
Now I know how to arrange the sculptures.
在外面等我
Wait for me outside.
然后怎么做
But what then?
怎么才能起作用
How does it work?
它们怎样才能带我去那里
How will they lead me to the place
那个藏宝的地方
Where the objects are hidden?
我不知道
I don't know.
把镯子还给我
Give that back.
你已经得到你想要的了
You have what you want.
你想活着离开这里吗  拉赛尔
Do you want to leave here alive, Lacell?
还有吗
Oh, Is there more?
真相将于黎明时揭晓
"The truth is in the dawn."
这是什么意思
What does it mean?
我不知道
I don't know.
真相将于黎明时揭晓
"The truth is in the dawn."
这是什么意思
What does it mean?
我不知道
I don't know!
I don't know.
我想你也不知道
I suppose you didn't know.
真相将于黎明时揭晓
"The truth is in the dawn.
"The truth is in the dawn."
我不知道这什么意思
I...I don't know what that means,
伯利的笔记本上写满了这句话
But it's...it's written all over Burleigh's notes.
都写了什么
What's...what's written?
黎明
Uh...dawn.
这个我不懂
Thi...I mean, I don't know.
也许是指造物
Uh, creation, maybe.
或是托尼・奥兰多的黎明乐队...
Tony Orlando and...
创造或毁灭
Creation...or destruction.
是的
Yeah.
阿迪  我们真的该相信这些东西吗
Look, Artie, how much of this stuff do we really believe?
如果他在找地洞  那我们就该相信
Well, enough that if he's looking for this cave,
而且要抢先他一步
It's better that we find it first.
我同意
I would agree with that.
你的搭档已经盯住我了
Your partner's already got me covered.
伙计  你快解释一下
Lucy, you've got some explaining to do.
密码在哪
So where's the code?
被吉尔伯特・列本捷足先登了
Gilbert Radburn beat me to it,
他也在找地洞
Same way he's been trying to find the cave.
什么地洞
What cave?
在地下的  神圣的  看看吧
Underground, sacred. Check it out.
我们必须阻止他
We have to stop him.
如你所说  有些东西
Like you said, there are some things
不该在世间流传
That should not be out in the world.
那个为你们俩工作的大个子呢
Yeah, well, what about that big guy that works for the two of you?
拉赛尔是雷纳佩人
Lacell is Lenape.
他也想保护那地洞
He want to save the cave too.
他在帮我监视着列本的挖掘工程
He's been my eyes at Radburn's digs.
他到现在还没联系我   估计大事不妙
He hasn't checked in either. I think something's happened.
我们必须先列本一步找到那个地洞
Okay, so we have to find this cave Before Radburn does.
如果他集齐四座雕像
Well, if he's got all four sculptures,
他可能已经在地洞里了
He could be there now.
我们手里有伯利所有的笔记
We've got all of Burleigh's note right here.
这不足以使我找到地洞
Well, that hasn't helped me solve it yet.
没错  韦佛先生
True, Mr. Weaver.
但你不是我
But...you're not me.
现在我们要赶在列本前
And right now we need to find the location of that cave
找到地洞
Before Radburn does.
真相将于黎明揭晓
The truth is in the dawn.
没错了  是张地图
Of course. It's a map.
谢谢了
Thank you.
伯利快要找到地洞的时候
So Burleigh stopped taking note
笔记也终止了
When he got close to finding the cave.
是的
Yeah.
就像是他意识到这个故事是真的
It's like he realize the stories were true
就停止了记录
And stopped writing anything down.
我想有这些就足够了
Well, you know, I think it may be enough
因为我找出了所有旧地图  我还...
Because I found all these old maps, and I...
芝麻开门
Knock knock.
你别打岔
I wish you wouldn't do that.
老天  这不好玩
God! Not funny.
等等
H...h...hang on.
我是回来拿工具的
I just came by to grab my tool
然后就踏上征程
And then I'm hitting the proverbial road.
我想去维加斯
I'm thinking Vegas.
真的吗  去维加斯  克劳迪娅
Really? Vegas, Claudia?
记住  押16  别押1
Remember, always hit on 16, never on 1."
那里一定有个雷纳佩族的聚居点
There's gotta be a lenape settlement here somewhere
一定是个安全的地方
And it's gotta be somewhere safe.
没错  他们找地方将特殊财产藏好
Yeah, and they'd look for a place with special properties.
那一定是个安全的地方
It's gotta be...it's gotta be somewhere safe.
那么  不是...
So...no, this is not...
你要干嘛
What...hey, hey!
伙计  你拿这些和远古龙脉比对过吗
Dude, have you considered matching these against magnetic ley line?
不  你别...
No, you don't...
有一条的走向恰好沿着这座岛的东岸
One runs right along the east edge of the island.
就在这里
Right there.
这是南面的...
This is the south...
在曼哈顿下的一个地洞
An underground cave in Manhattan, huh?
如果这些年来  还没人
You know, if no one's run into it...
找到它的话  那我们可以排除
In all these year, then we can eliminate
那些主要的公共枢纽
Everywhere where they've dug for major utility junctions...
还有地铁  就是这里
And subways. This looks right.
错不了的
Indeed it does.
伙计们  我想我找到了  找到了
Guys, I think I've got it. I've got it.
它就位于洛伊赛德[下东区]
It is at Lower East Side.
也就是"克莱尔角"  就在...
Corlear's Hook. that is, um...
就在威廉斯堡大桥的南面
That is just south of the Williamsburg Bridge,
离河较近
And it's right near the water,
离地铁较远
And it's gotta be away from the subway lines.
克劳迪娅指出...
And Claudia pointed...out...
那个...
The...uh...
列本的大楼就在那里
Radburn's building there.
他到处在挖伯利考察过的地点
He's been digging everywhere that Burleigh focused
明修栈道  暗渡陈仓
Using new construction to over his hunt.
他快找到地洞了
Then he's close to finding it.
好了  阿迪  我们要出发了
Okay, Artie, we're heading out.
好的  抓紧时间
Yeah, okay, feel free to hurry.
好的
Yeah.
我要到那里去
All right, I need to get right here.
就在洞穴的旁边  需要多久
Right next to this cave. How long will that take?
我们能在五分钟内把那炸开
We can blow it in five minutes.
我要洞穴里的东西完整无缺
I need the contents of the cave to be intact.
所有东西原封不动
Nothing can be disturbed.
里面有东西吗
Contents?
如果进行精确爆破
Well, if it's a surgical blow,
能在它旁边炸开
I say we blast right here next to it
然后用手提钻从侧面钻开最后几英尺
And go sideways the last couple of feet by jackhammer.
你只要带我去洞边
You just get me next to that cave.
其他的我来处理
I'll take care of everything else.
-开工吧  -好的
- Let's go.  - Okay.
引爆
Fire in the hole!
好了  行动吧
All right, let's do it!
洞穴离那堵墙只有十八英寸
Your site's just 18 inches the other side of that wall.
我去找些人来钻洞
Let me get a couple guys with jackhammer.
任何人都不准过来  听懂没
No one come near here, you undertand?
这是真的
It's true.
全是真的
It's all true.
长生不老水
The water of eternal life.
赐我自然神力
He shall have the power of nature herself.
等等  等等
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
吉尔伯特・列本在哪
Gilbert Radburn. Where is he?
在引爆点  我要走了
Down in the blast site. But I'm getting out of here.
进去
Let's go.
赐我百人之力
He shall have the strength of a hundred men.
赐我驾驭大地的力量
And he shall harness the strength of the earth.
你可够忙的啊
Hey, you kind of got your hands full, don't you?
别  吉尔
Don't, Gil.
你根本不知道自己在干什么
You don't know what you're dealing with.
你来晚了  杰弗
You're too late, Jeff.
这是我的使命
This is what I was meant to do.
-神经病  -不可理喻
- Nut bag.  - The nuttiest.
好了  列本  把箭放下
Okay, Radburn, drop the arrow.
把它放回去  吉尔  这不属于我们
Put it back, Gil. It's not for us.
也不是你的  杰弗  你太弱了
Not for you, Jeff. You're weak.
你父亲也是个窝囊废
And so was your father.
听我说
Listen to me.
你不知道你在干嘛
You don't know what you're doing.
第四个元素会完成转变
The fourth element completes the transformation.
那时我将所向披靡
Then nothing can stop me.
这地方做你的坟墓再合适不过了
How fitting that this place should be your tomb.
不要  这不是属于你的
No, no, no, it's not meant for you.
它们属于能够驾驭它们的强人
They are meant for the man who's strong enough to use them.
-芝麻开门  -老天  别闹了
- Knock knock.  - Oh, god. Don't do that!
永远都这么好玩  对吧
That just never stops being funny, Don't you think?
是啊  "永远"  你在干嘛
Oh, never. What are you doing...
在维加斯过得如何
What happened with Vegas?
-太简单了  -你不会
- It was too easy.  - You didn't.
弄了点零用钱
Just a little pocket money.
你不想上大学或者
Shouldn't you be in college or something?
不想和你同龄人待在一起吗
Don't you want to be with people your own age?
阿迪  我跟同龄人不一样
Artie, I'm not my own age.
得了
Come on.
写英语论文  参加兄弟会派对
Writing English paper and going to frat parties?
无聊死了
Bor-ing!
至少在这里
I mean, at least here, you know,
还有些挑战性
There's, um... there's a challenge.
是很有挑战
That there is.
你准备好了吗
You up for it?
问题是  老头...
Question is, geezer...
你准备好了吗
Are you?
你太自不量力了
Oh, you are so out of your league.
《十三号仓库》第一季 第六集
Warehouse 13 S01E06
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译制作
更多美剧下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
翻译： 童霹雳     katarina     小废废
时间轴：  地下铁        校对：  Finger大侠  何何
后期：渔夫       字幕总监制：何何